Guide to the Torch Honor Society, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Torch Honor Society, Yale University, records
1916-2017
RU 72
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.83
(11 boxes)
The records consist of the constitution, member lists, correspondence, minutes,and printed materials documenting initiations, office plans, and general activities of the Torch Honor Society at Yale.
Yale University. Torch Honor Society
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Accessions 19ND-A-484 and 1991-A-089 are open for research. Use of all other accessions requires written permission from the president of the Fax Facis Foundation. Contact a Reference Archivist for more information.
Biographical / Historical
The Torch Honor Society was founded on March 8, 1916 for the purpose of bestowing recognition of merit and achievement upon deserving students. Each year the society elected ten juniors who were outstanding in various University activities irrespective of society or fraternity affiliation. Their symbol, the uplifted torch, was chosen to signify their allegiance to the Yale creed "Lux et Veritas" (Light and Truth) as well as devotion to their own ideals - enlightening leadership and beneficent service. A broad circle supporting the torch symbolizes equality and comradeship in mutual endeavors, while a third symbol, the Roman numeral X, marks the initial class unit of ten adopted by the founders, and is set across and within the broad circle encompassing the central design. The society selected two professors as charter members, and has conferred honorary titles upon Yale graduates and faculty. The society has re-formed as an organizaton beginning in 1995.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of the constitution, member lists, correspondence, minutes, and printed materials documenting initiations, office plans, and general activities of the Torch Honor Society at Yale.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Accessions 2016-A-027 and 2017-A-062 were gifts of Fax Facis Foundation, 2015 and 2017.
College students -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Torch Honor Society
- Records, 1916-1967; Accession 19ND-A-484
  Scope and Contents
  Non-permanent financial records, including receipts, bank statements, and checkbooks were destroyed in 2008.
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Minutes, 1916-1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1926-1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1940-1944, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes of Annual Dinner, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Constitution, by-laws and minutes, 1956-1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Permanent records, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters, notes, 1924-1945 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, 1946-1956 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Official publications and recommendations, 1944-1951 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Investigation of residential college plan, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Notebook: guidelines, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - History of the founding of the society, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Alumni elections, initiation banquets, and miscellaneous correspondence, 1929-1960 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Alumni notes, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Initiation ceremonies, 1946-1954 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Invitations to membership: cards, Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - "The Criticisms", Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Essays on Yale, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Newsclippings (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Newsclippings (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Newsclippings (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Newsclippings (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Catalogues, 1940-1956 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Members, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Sheffield Scientific School: class List, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Sheffield Scientific School: class list, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Sheffield Scientific School: class list, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Classbooks, vol, I (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Classbooks, vol. II (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Classbooks, vol. III (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - The Aurelian Honor Society: members, 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Treasurer"s records, 1944-1951 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Members " accounts (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Photographs (Box 6, Folder 48)
- Records, 1916-1933; Accession 1991-A-089
  - Constitution Papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Incorporation, 1921 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Torch Honor Society": history, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Members, circa 1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Initiation, circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence
    - Hogan, Edward, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - LaRoche, Chester J., 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - O"Hearn, Charles M., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Roe, Joseph W., 1923-1932 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Schreiber, Carl F., 1917-1920, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - General, 1916-1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Secondary Schools, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Records, 1917-2013; Accession 2016-A-0015
  Use of this material requires written permission from the president of the Fax Facis Foundation. Contact a Reference Archivist for more information.
  - Administrative procedures in government agencies documents, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1917-1933, 1971,1997-2013, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-22)
  - Founding class scrapbook, 1917 (Box 2)
- Biographical booklets for the delegations of the classes of 2007-2015, Accession 2016-A-027
  - Biographical booklets for the delegations of the classes of 2007-2015 (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
- Biographical booklets for the delegations of the classes of 2016-2017, Accession 2017-A-062
  - Biographical booklets for the delegations of the classes of 2016-2017 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    There are two copies of the booklet for each year, one with color images and one in black and white.